

s.philippart@gmail.com

**J** +33 6 70 23 86 01

● French

Paris/France Timezone

philippart-s.github.io/blog/

in philippartstephane

philippart-s

@philippart-s

<u>≥</u> 2471248/wilda

Resume PDF

#### **EDUCATION**

**Engineer in Computer Science**Polytech Tours

DUT Informatique

BAC D

Lycée Claude de France à Romoranti

#### LANGUAGES

rench (Native)

English (Professional)

### INTERESTS

Co-creator of TADx meetup

Running

Cooking

# **CAREER PROFILE**

After many years spent in the world of development, expertise and software architecture I chose to change path. Indeed, the relationship with developers being a very important element for me I decided to become Developer Relation.

Sharing is an essential element for me: that's why I co-created an association whose goal is to organize meetups around agility and DevOps: TADx. Always in order to share I am also a speaker at conferences.

## **EXPERIENCES**

Developer Relation

2022 - Today

OVHcloud, Paris

Developer Advocate within the OVHcloud public cloud teams and more specifically Artificial Intelligence and native cloud.

Zero client with product teams to test products.

Technical writer for official guides and company blog posts.

Participation in conferences as a speaker and stand management. Animations of development communities internally and externally.

POC development and demos.

Software Architect / Platform engineer

2008 - 2022

Harmonie-Mutuelle, Tours

Provision of bases for development teams: Spring, JEE, Angular, Business Works (ESB). Development of internal frameworks (based on SpringBoot & Angular).

Design and implementation of the continuous integration platform based on Jenkins 2 ("pipelines as code"), SonarQube and GitHub.

Implementation of the "CI / CD" channel on OpenShift.

Java / JEE Software Engineer

2006 - 2008

Apside TOP, Tours

Implementation of web applications as a JEE expert in service at Coface Services and support of internal staff in their skills development.

Role of tech lead within the teams.

## Head of Technical Project

2004 - 2006

Delta Informatique, Tours

Websites development (banking and insurance sector) in JEE (deployed on Weblogic) as expert developer and then technical project manager (technical specifications, development and implementation at customers) on the same technologies.

#### Java / JEE Engineer

2002 - 2004

Prima Solutions, Paris

Front end and back end development in the insurance sector and for the website assurland.com. Customer support for the deployment of JEE / Weblogic solutions.

## PROJECTS

TADx - Co-creator of a meetup in Tours. This meetup aims to organize one event per month around the various and varied topics that can be found in the IT ecosystem.

Blog personnel - Personal blog to share around technical topics.

Conférences données - Slides and videos of the conferences given.

# S OSS CONTRIBUTIONS

Jenkins conventional commits plugin - Jenkins plugin allowing automatic calculation of versions based on commit messages.

Developers Conferences Agenda/List - Repository for centralizing conference dates and

LangChain4j - Repository for using LLM within Java applications.

# SKILLS & PROFICIENCY

